<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Caravan</string>

    <string name="ace_name">Ace</string>
    <string name="two_name">Two</string>
    <string name="three_name">Three</string>
    <string name="four_name">Four</string>
    <string name="five_name">Five</string>
    <string name="six_name">Six</string>
    <string name="seven_name">Seven</string>
    <string name="eight_name">Eight</string>
    <string name="nine_name">Nine</string>
    <string name="ten_name">Ten</string>
    <string name="jack_name">Jack</string>
    <string name="queen_name">Queen</string>
    <string name="king_name">King</string>
    <string name="joker_name">Joker</string>

    <string name="hearts_name">of Hearts</string>
    <string name="clubs_name">of Clubs</string>
    <string name="diamonds_name">of Diamonds</string>
    <string name="spades_name">of Spades</string>

    <string name="standard_deck_name">standard deck</string>
    <string name="tops_deck_name">Tops deck</string>
    <string name="lucky_38_deck_name">Lucky 38 deck</string>
    <string name="ultra_luxe_deck_name">Ultra-Luxe deck</string>
    <string name="gomorrah_deck_name">Gomorrah deck</string>
    <string name="sierra_madre_deck_name">Sierra Madre deck</string>

    <string name="menu_pve">Quick game</string>
    <string name="menu_pvp">Multiplayer</string>
    <string name="menu_tutorial">Tutorial</string>
    <string name="menu_rules">Rules</string>
    <string name="menu_deck">Deck Settings</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <string name="menu_discord" translatable="false">Discord!</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_back">Back to menu</string>

    <string name="deck_select">Select the Deck</string>
    <string name="deck_select_about">Win new decks by defeating enemies in a balanced game (w/o using custom deck).</string>
    <string name="deck_custom">Set Custom Deck</string>
    <string name="deck_custom_about">Win cards for custom deck by fighting opponents:\n1 or 2 cards when using custom deck,\n4 cards when playing balanced game.\nThe chance of winning _new_ card, however, is not 100%.</string>

    <string name="custom_deck_size">Deck size: %1$s\n(must be at least %2$s)</string>
    <string name="custom_deck_non_faces">Number of non-face cards: %1$s\n(must be at least %2$s)</string>

    <string name="pve_select_enemy">Select the Opponent</string>
    <string name="pve_enemy_easy">Ultra-Luxe visitor</string>
    <string name="pve_enemy_medium">Thug from Gomorrah</string>
    <string name="pve_enemy_queen">Swank from Tops</string>
    <string name="pve_enemy_38">Securitron P373</string>
    <string name="pve_enemy_cheater">Courier Six</string>
    <string name="pve_use_custom_deck">Use Custom Deck</string>
    <string name="pve_stats">Stats</string>
    <string name="pve_games_started">Games started: %1$s</string>
    <string name="pve_games_finished">Games finished: %1$s</string>
    <string name="pve_games_won">Games won: %1$s</string>
    <string name="pve_percentiles">Rates</string>
    <string name="pve_w_to_l">Success coefficient (W/L): %1$s</string>
    <string name="pve_w_to_finished">Win rate (W/Finished): %1$s \%%</string>
    <string name="pve_w_to_started">Win-No-Quit rate (W/Started): %1$s \%%</string>
    <string name="pve_finished_to_started">No-Quit rate (Finished/Started): %1$s \%%</string>
    <string name="custom_deck_is_too_small">Custom deck is too small!</string>
    <string name="custom_deck_is_too_small_message">Deck has less than 30 cards or less than 15 numbered cards!</string>
    <string name="you_win">You win!</string>
    <string name="result">Result</string>
    <string name="you_lose">You lose!</string>
    <string name="you_have_unlocked_deck">\nYou have unlocked the %1$s!</string>
    <string name="you_must_unlock_deck">\nTo have a chance of winning cards from the %1$s, you must defeat the enemy w/o custom deck!</string>
    <string name="your_prize_cards_from">\nYour reward - cards from %1$s:\n</string>

    <string name="new_card">New: %1$s.\n</string>
    <string name="old_card">Old: %1$s.\n</string>

    <string name="discard_card">DISCARD CARD</string>
    <string name="drop_caravan">DROP CARAVAN #%1$s</string>
    <string name="back_to_menu">Back to Menu</string>
    <string name="back_to_main_menu">Back to Main Menu</string>

    <string name="about_1">Caravan is the card game from video game \"Fallout: New Vegas\", created by Obsidian and Bethesda.</string>
    <string name="about_2">This port is created by subject_name_here (it\'s a username, not a bug!), who is in no way affiliated with the creators of the original game.</string>
    <string name="about_3_1">"If you want to request some features or report bugs, contact me at "</string>
    <string name="about_3_2">. You can also leave a review in Play Store.</string>
    <string name="about_4_1">"The Caravan rules and tutorial are heavily based on "</string>
    <string name="about_4_2">this Reddit post</string>
    <string name="about_4_3">. You can thank its creator by upvote.</string>

    <string name="rules">ORIGINAL RULES\nCaravan is played with two players building three opposing piles (or \"caravans\") of numbered cards. The goal is to outbid your opponent\'s caravan with the highest value of numbered cards without being too light (under 21) or overburdened (over 26).\n\nThe game begins with each player taking eight cards from their deck and placing either one numerical card or ace on each caravan. Players may not discard during this initial round.\n\nOnce both players have started their three caravans, each player may do ONE of the following on their turn:\n1. Play one card and draw a new card from his or her deck to their hand.\n2. Discard one card from their hand and draw a new card from his or her deck.\n3. Disband one of their three caravans by removing all cards from that pile.\n\nCaravans have a direction, either ascending or descending numerically, and a suit. The suit is determined with the first card placed on a caravan, the direction by the second. All subsequent cards must continue the numerical direction or match the suit of the previous card. Cards of the same numerical value cannot be played in sequence, regardless of suit. Face cards can be attached to numeric cards in any caravan and affects them in various ways.\n\nCARD VALUES\nJoker: Played against ace, 2–10. Effects change based on whether it\'s an ace or a numbered card (see below). Multiple jokers may be played on the same card.\n\nAce: Value of 1. Jokers played on aces remove all other non–face cards of the ace\'s suit from the table. E.g. a joker played on an Ace of Spades removes all spades (except face cards and that card, specifically) from the table.\n\n2–10: Listed value. Jokers played on these cards remove all other cards of this value from the table. E.g. a joker played on a 4 of Hearts removes all 4s (other than that card, specifically) from the table.\n\nJack: Played against ace, 2–10. Removes that card, along with any face cards attached to it.\n\nQueen: Played against ace, 2–10. Reverses the current direction of the hand and changes the current suit of the hand. Multiple queens may be played on the same card.\n\nKing: Played against ace, 2–10. Adds the value of that card again. E.g. a king played on a 9 adds 9 to that hand. Multiple kings may be played on the same card for multiplicative effects. E.g. 4+ king = 8. 4 + 2 kings = 16.\n\nWINNING\nA player\'s caravan is considered sold when the value of its cards is over 20 and under 27. The other player may still outbid by increasing the value of their opposing pile while staying within the 21–26 range. When each of the three competing caravans has sold, the game is over. In the event that one of the three caravan values are tied between players, the game continues until all three caravans have sold. The player with two or more sales wins the pot.</string>
    <string name="kyle">Kyle says:</string>
    <string name="tutorial_1_1">Howdy! Fine hot day for a Sarsaparilla, ain\'t it?\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_1_2">Days like this are the reason why I ain\'t leaving Mojave, not for anything.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_2">While we wait, how about a game of Caravan?</string>
    <string name="tutorial_3">You don\'t know the rules? Ain\'t a problem. Gonna teach you while we are waiting.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_5">Your deck now has only ten cards. That is only for teaching you. In the field your deck is bigger.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6_1">Usually people of Mojave play with custom decks.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6_2">I then say \'sticks and stones\' and whip out the deck of 6s and 10s and Ks.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_6_3">After I beat them, they don\'t play with me no more. That\'s why I prefer balanced rules.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_7">In balanced rules both players start with a full deck o\' 54. It is more - you guessed it - balanced.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_8_1">Each player has three caravans - left, central and right.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_9_1">The game starts like this: we take 8 cards from our decks to our hand.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_9_2">Then we have to start the caravans by placing an ace or 2–10 card on top of each of our caravans.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_10">To place a card on top of a caravan, select it in your hand and then click the brown rectangle with yellow border.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_11">Now start your caravans.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_12">Good job.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_13">You might ask: \'What if all 8 cards are, let\'s say, Jacks and Kings, and no aces or 2–10?\'</string>
    <string name="tutorial_14">Well, if you play with someone else, you\'d have to reshuffle your deck.\nMe though, I never had that.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_15_1">Sometimes there is a rule that you can discard the card during the opening phase.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_15_2">If you ask me, it seems like a huge advantage, so we ain\'t.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_16">Now the game begins truly. You have a choice of four.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_17">Let\'s start with discarding cards from your hand. It is the easiest one.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_18">Select any card, and the discard button will appear on your right. When you press it, the card is gone.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_19">Now, discard any face card, preferably Queen.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_warning">Warning!</string>
    <string name="tutorial_20_1">You can do, actually, whatever you want. You can discard a non-face card or put a card onto a caravan.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_20_2">However, it is like travelling to Vegas through the north - may break the game, difficult and not worth it ;)</string>
    <string name="tutorial_21_1">"Nice. Have you noticed that a card was added in your hand? "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_21_2">There are always 5 cards in your hand, unless your deck is empty.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_22">Now let\'s talk about how to build a caravan. You do it with aces or 2–10 cards.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_23">Each of those cards has a value: 1 for ace, 2 for 2,… 10 for 10.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_24">However, you cannot just put any card. You can\'t put on top of a caravan the card of the same rank as the caravan\'s current top card.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_25">Also, you have to follow one of two rules:</string>
    <string name="tutorial_26_1">"either the card you want to add to a caravan has the same suit as the caravan's current top card, "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_26_2">or its rank follows the caravan\'s numerical sequence.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27_1">Numerical sequence is determined by the top two cards of the caravan.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27_2">If the top rank is greater than the pre-top card rank, the new card must have a value greater than the top.\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27_3">If the top rank is less than the pre-top card rank, the new card must have a value less than the top.\n\n</string>
    <string name="tutorial_27_4">In raider\'s terms: if it\'s bigger - go even bigger, if it\'s smaller - go even smaller.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_28">Now put all non-face cards onto caravans. Try to build a long one. Show me how you understood the rules.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_hint">Hint!</string>
    <string name="tutorial_29">You can discard cards, Kyle won\'t notice.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_30">Well done. Building a caravan is the most difficult part of the game.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_31">You can also disband caravans. You should do it, if its value is too big to handle with Jacks and Jokers.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_32">To disband a caravan, tap its value. To your right the button will appear. Press it, and the caravan is gone.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_33">Disband all your caravans.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_34">Now let us talk about Jacks, Queens, Kings and Jokers.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_35">You put them not on top of a caravan, but on one of the caravan\'s cards. Hell, even on the cards from my caravan.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_36">First of all: you can put only three cards on a card, unless it is Jack.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_37">King, if you put it on a card, doubles the total value of that card.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_38">Jack just removes the card from a caravan, with all its face cards.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_39">Queen reverses the current numerical direction of the caravan, and changes the suit of the caravan to that of the Queen.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_40">Finally, Joker. It is like Jack, but way more powerful.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_41">If you put Joker onto an ace of some suit, all other number cards from both player\'s caravans that share the same suit of the ace are removed.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_42">If you put Joker onto a 2–10 card, all other number cards of the same rank from both player\'s caravans are removed.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_43">The card you have put Joker onto is safe for now. However, if any other Joker is played, that card can be removed.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_44">Hard, I know. But it is the hardest part - remembering what face cards do.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_45">Now get rid of all cards from your hand. Use face cards on my cards.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_46">Congratulations! You have lost!</string>
    <string name="tutorial_47">You have no cards to build a caravan with. It means I win.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_48">However, it is rare for the game of Caravan to end like this.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_8_2">Caravans in the same column - opposing - are competing with each other.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_49_1">"The game\'s target is to sell two or three of your caravans at a higher sum, or \"bid\", "</string>
    <string name="tutorial_49_2">than the opposing caravan. The bid is determined by the cards in the caravan.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_50">A caravan is considered sold when its bid is within 21–26 range; any bid that is higher or lower is not a sold caravan.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_51">Usually, the game is over when in each of the opposing caravan pairs one of the caravans is sold at the higher bid.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_52">If two caravans are sold with the same bid, the game continues until one of the caravans has a higher bid, but no more than 26.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_53">That\'s it. I am not going to tell all my tricks, you should figure the game out yourself.</string>
    <string name="tutorial_56">See ya round.</string>

    <string name="create_room">Create Room (you go first)</string>
    <string name="failure">Failure!</string>
    <string name="incorrect_room_number">Incorrect room number!</string>
    <string name="your_room_is">Your Room is %1$s. Awaiting the Opponent.....</string>
    <string name="private_room">Private room</string>
    <string name="find">Join any Room!!!</string>
    <string name="pool">Requesting room…</string>
    <string name="join">Join Room (you go second)</string>
    <string name="room_number">Room</string>
    <string name="no_stats_here">No stats here: the game\'s for fun, not for numbers!</string>
    <string name="pvp_piece">
        Just press \"Join any Room!!!\", if you:\n
        - want to find anyone.\n
        - saw notification from bot on Discord.\n
        If not, well, here is manual:\n
        To create room:\n
        - enter room number (if one number fails, try another),\n
        - select room privacy setting, \n
        - whether you want to play with custom deck or not, \n
        - press \"Create Room\".\n
        Room number is - NEW!!! - from 25000 to 30000. OLD NUMBERS WON\'T WORK!!!\n
        \n
        If someone gave you a room number, enter it and press \"Join Room\". No checkboxes are necessary.\n
        \n
        Sometimes first connection to server might take a long time, like, ~2 minutes.
        Action timeout (move, room waiting) is ~38 seconds, then the room is destroyed.
    </string>

    <string name="discard">Discard!</string>
    <string name="wait">Wait…</string>
    <string name="init_stage">Init stage!</string>
    <string name="can_t_act">Can\'t act!</string>
    <string name="your_turn">Your turn!</string>

    <string name="get_notifications_about_multiplayer">"Get notifications about multiplayer: "</string>

</resources>
